This is my niece, Stella.
هذه ابنة أخي ستيلا
She's just turned one and started to walk.
بلغت للتو السنة من العمر و بدأت بالمشي.
And she's walking in that really cool way that one-year-olds do,
و هي تمشي بتلك الطريقة الرائعة ككل الأطفال
a kind of teetering, my-body's-moving- too-fast-for-my-legs kind of way.
في سنتهم الأولى حيث يتمايلون
It is absolutely gorgeous.
إنها رائعة بكل تأكيد.
And one of her favorite things to do at the moment
و من أكثر الأشياء المفضلة لديها حاليا
is to stare at herself in the mirror.
هي أن تحدق بنفسها في المرآة.
She absolutely loves her reflection.
فهي بكل تأكيد تحب انعكاسها على المرآة.
She giggles and squeals, and gives herself these big, wet kisses.
و تضحك و تتقهقه
It is beautiful.
إنه شيء جميل.
Apparently, all of her friends do this and my mom tells me that I used to do this,
و يبدو إن كل أصدقائها يقومون بذلك
and it got me thinking:
و هذا دعاني للتفكير
When did I stop doing this?
متى توقفت عن فعل ذلك ؟
When is it suddenly not okay to love the way that we look?
متى صار فجأة غير محبذ ان نحب مظهرنا؟
Because apparently we don't.
لأنه من الواضح أننا لا نحب مظهرنا
Ten thousand people every month google,
في كل شهر يبحث عشرة آلاف شخص على قوقل
"Am I ugly?"
"هل أنا قبيح ؟"
This is Faye. Faye is 13 and she lives in Denver.
هذه فاي, عمرها 13 عام وتعيش في دنفر
And like any teenager, she just wants to be liked and to fit in.
و كأي مراهق تريد أن تكون محبوبة و مقبولة.
It's Sunday night.
إنها ليلة يوم الأحد
She's getting ready for the week ahead at school.
و هي تستعد للمدرسة في الأسبوع المقبل
And she's slightly dreading it, and she's a bit confused because
و هي خائفة قليلة و محتارة لأنها
despite her mom telling her all the time
بالرغم من أن والدتها تخبرها طوال الوقت
that she's beautiful,
أنها جميلة
every day at school, someone tells her that she's ugly.
كل يوم في المدرسة،
Because of the difference between what her mom tells her and what her friends
و بسبب الاختلاف بين ما تقوله والدتها
at school, or her peers at school are telling her,
و ما يقوله أقرانها في المدرسة
she doesn't know who to believe.
لا تعلم من تصدق
So, she takes a video of herself. She posts it to YouTube
لذلك تصور فيديو لنفسها و تضعه على اليوتيوب
and she asks people to please leave a comment:
و تسأل الناس و تطلب منهم أن يكتبوا تعليق
"Am I pretty or am I ugly?"
"هل أنا جميلة أم قبيحة ؟"
Well, so far, Faye has received over 13,000 comments.
حسناً، حتى الآن فاي حصلت على 13000 تعليق
Some of them are so nasty, they don't bear thinking about.
بعض من التعليقات مقرفة، حتى أنهم لم يتكبدوا عناء التفكير بذلك
This is an average, healthy-looking teenage girl receiving this feedback
هذه فتاة مراهقة بمظهر صحي عادي
at one of the most emotionally vulnerable times in her life.
في أكثر الأوقات العاطفية الحساسة من حياتها
Thousands of people are posting videos like this,
الآلاف من الناس ينشرون فيديوهات كهذا،
mostly teenage girls, reaching out in this way.
معظمهم فيتات مراهقات يتواصلون بهذه الطريقة
But what's leading them to do this?
لكن ما الذي دفعهم لفعل ذلك ؟
Well, today's teenagers are rarely alone.
حسناً المراهقون هذه الأيام نادراً ما يكونون وحيدين.
talking, messaging, liking, commenting, sharing, posting —
يتكلمون و يرسلون الرسائل و يعجبون
it never ends.
هذا لا ينتهي أبداً.
Never before have we been so connected,
لم يسبق لنا أبداً أن كنا بهذا التواصل
so continuously, so instantaneously, so young.
بهذا الشكل المستمر و الفوري و بأعمار شابة
There's simply no privacy.
بكل بساطة, لا يوجد هناك اي خصوصية.
And the social pressures that go along with that are relentless.
و الضغوط الاجتماعية التي ترافق هذا قاسية
based on the number of likes they get
حسب عدد الإعجابات التي يحصلون عليها
and the types of comments that they receive.
و نوع التعليقات التي يتلقونها
There's no separation between online and offline life.
لا يوجد فصل بين الحياة على الشبكة
What's real or what isn't is really hard to tell the difference between.
من الصعب التمييز
And it's also really hard to tell the difference between what's authentic
و أيضاً من الصعب التمييز بين ما هو أصلي
and what's digitally manipulated.
و ما هو متلاعب به رقمياً.
What's a highlight in someone's life versus what's normal in the context of everyday.
ما هو الحدث المهم مقابل الأحداث اليومية العادية
And where are they looking to for inspiration?
و أين يبحثون على الإلهام؟
Well, you can see the kinds of images that are covering the newsfeeds
لنرى نوعية الصور اللي تملأ
of girls today.
مصادر أخبار الفتيات هذه الأيام
Airbrushing is now routine.
صار من المعتاد إعادة رسم ملامح الوجة
And trends like #thinspiration, #thighgap,
و أصبحنا نرى هاشتاقات عن النحافة
#bikinibridge and #proana.
و عن الفراغ بين الفخذين
For those who don't know, #proana means pro-anorexia.
وهاشتاقات تشجع على فقدان الشهية
These trends are teamed with the stereotyping and flagrant objectification
هذه التوجهات تصاحبها نظرة مادية بحتة
of women in today's popular culture.
للمرأة في الثقافة العامة
It is not hard to see what girls are benchmarking themselves against.
ليس صعبا معرفة ما تقارن الفتيات به أنفسهن
But boys are not immune to this either.
لكن الاولاد ليسوا محصنين من هذا ايضا
Aspiring to the chiseled jaw lines and ripped six packs of superhero-like sports stars
نراهم يطمحون للفك العريض والعضلات المشدودة
and playboy music artists.
كنجوم الرياضة و المغنين
But, what's the problem with all of this?
لكن, ماهي المشكلة في كل هذا؟
Well, surely we want our kids to grow up as healthy, well balanced individuals.
طبعا نريد ان ينشأ ابناؤنا كأفراد متزنين
But in an image-obsessed culture, we are training our kids
ولكن بثقافة مههوسة بالشكل، نحن نربيهم
to spend more time and mental effort on their appearance
على قضاء الوقت والجهد بالإهتمام بمظهرهم
at the expense of all of the other aspects of their identities.
على حساب الجوانب الأخرى من هويتهم
So, things like their relationships, the development of their physical abilities,
كعلاقاتهم الإجتماعية و مهاراتهم البدنية
and their studies and so on begin to suffer.
و تحصيلهم الدراسي... التي تبدأ بالتدهور
Six out of 10 girls are now choosing not to do something because they don't
6 من 10 فتيات يختارون عدم القيام بمهمة
think they look good enough.
لإعتقادهم أنهم ليسوا بالجمال الكافي
These are not trivial activities.
نحن لا نتحدث عن أنشطة ثانوية
These are fundamental activities to their development as humans
بل أنشطة أساسية لنضجهم كأفراد
and as contributors to society and to the workforce.
وكأشخاص مساهمين في المجتمع
Thirty-one percent, nearly one in three teenagers, are withdrawing
٣٠٪ ، ما يقارب ١ من كل ٣ مراهقين
from classroom debate. They're failing
ينسحبون من النقاشات في الصف
to engage in classroom debate because
لا يشاركون لأنهم لا يريدون
they don't want to draw attention to the way that they look.
لفت الإنتباة إلى مظهرهم
One in five are not showing up to class at all
واحد من كل خمسة يتغيب عن المدرسة
on days when they don't feel good about it.
عندما لا يكون راضيا عن مظهره
And when it comes to exams,
دعونا نتحدث عن الإختبارات
if you don't think you look good enough,
عندما تعتقد أنك لا تبدو بشكل جيد
specifically if you don't think you are thin enough,
خصوصا إذا كنت تظن أنك لست رشيقا
you will score a lower grade point average
فإن درجتك ستقل عن درجات زملائك
than your peers who are not concerned with this.
الذين لا يقلقون بالتفكير بهذا الأمر
And this is consistent across Finland, the U.S.
وهذا ثبت في فنلندا و الولايات المتحدة
and China, and is true regardless of how much you actually weigh.
والصين ،و بغض النظر عن وزنك الحقيقي
So to be super clear, we're talking about the
وللتوضيح أكثر، نحن نتحدث عن
way you think you look, not how you actually look.
اعتقادك عن شكلك و ليس شكلك الحقيقي
Low body confidence is undermining academic achievement.
قلة الثقة بالمظهر تخفض المستوى الدراسي
But it's also damaging health.
و تدمر الصحة
Teenagers with low body confidence do less physical activity,
حينما تقل ثقة المراهق بمظهره
eat less fruits and vegetables,
فإنه يتمرن أقل و لايأكل الفواكة والخضروات
partake in more unhealthy weight control practices
و يقوم بحميات غذائية غير صحية
that can lead to eating disorders.
والتي تؤدي إلى اضطرابات الأكل
They have lower self-esteem.
وينخفض لديه مستوى تقدير الذات
They're more easily influenced by people around them
مما يجعله أكثر تأثرا بآراء الآخرين
and they're at greater risk of depression.
ويعرضه للإصابة بالإكتئاب
And we think it's for all of these reasons that they take more risks
وكل هذه الأمور تجعلهم أكثر قابلية
with things like alcohol and drug use;
لشرب الكحول و تعاطي المخدرات
crash dieting; cosmetic surgery; unprotected, earlier sex;
و الأكل غير الصحي و جراحات التجميل
and self-harm.
و الإنخراط في ممارسات جنسية و إيذاء أنفسهم
The pursuit of the perfect body is putting pressure on our healthcare systems
السعي خلف الجسم المثالي يستنزف المستشفيات
and costing our governments billions of dollars every year.
و يكلف حكوماتنا بلايين الدولارات كل سنة
And we don't grow out of it.
و لا نكف عنه
Women who think they're overweight — again,
النساء اللواتي يظنن بأنهن سمينات
regardless of whether they are or are not —
بغض النظر عما إذا كانوا كذلك بالفعل
have higher rates of absenteeism.
يتغيبن عن العمل بنسبة أكبر
Seventeen percent of women would
١٧٪ من النساء لن تأتي
not show up to a job interview on
لتجري مقابلة عمل في اليوم الذي
a day when they weren't feeling confident about the way that they look.
لا تشعر فيه بالثقة بمظهرها
Have a think about what this is doing
دعونا نفكر بأثر ذلك
to our economy.
على اقتصادنا
opportunity looks like.
إن تغلبنا على هذا
Unlocking this potential is in the interest
اتاحة هذه الإمكانيات
of every single one of us.
يصب في مصلحة كل فرد منا
But how do we do that?
ولكن كيف نفعل ذلك؟
Well, talking, on its own, only gets you so far.
التحدث وحده عن المشكلات
It's not enough by itself.
لا يكفي لحلها
If you actually want to make a difference,
إن اردنا أن نحدث تغييرا
you have to do something.
فيجب علينا فعل شيء
And we've learned there are three key ways:
هناك ثلاث طرق لصنع التغيير
The first is we have to educate for body confidence.
أولها التوعية بأهمية الثقة بالشكل
We have to help our teenagers develop
يجب علينا تعليم المراهقين
strategies to overcome image-related pressures
كيفية التغلب عل ضغط الظهور بشكل مثالي
and build their self-esteem.
وكيف يبنون احترامهم لذواتهم
Now, the good news is that there are
من الجيد وجود برامج تعنى بذلك حاليا
The bad news is that most of them don't work.
ولكن لسوء الحظ
I was shocked to learn that many well-meaning
صدمت عندما عرفت
programs are inadvertently actually
أن الكثير من هذه البرامج الجيدة
making the situation worse.
تزيد الأمر سوءا من غير قصد
So we need to make damn sure that
ولهذا يجب علينا التأكد قطعيا
the programs that our kids are receiving
أن أطفالنا لا يتلقون برامج
are not only having a positive impact,
لا تترك آثار ايجابية فقط
but having a lasting impact as well.
بل تترك تأثيرا دائما
And the research shows that the best programs
أظهرت الدراسات أن أفضل
address six key areas:
برامج التوعية تخاطب ٦ جوانب أساسية
The first is the influence of family, friends and relationships.
أولها تأثير العائلة و الأصدقاء و العلاقات
The second is media and celebrity culture,
ثانيا تأثير الإعلام والمشاهير
then how to handle teasing and bullying,
ثم التعامل مع المضايقات وأذى الأقران
the way we compete and compare with one another
كيف ننافس ونقارن أنفسنا بالآخرين
based on looks,
بناء على أشكالنا
talking about appearance — some people
و التحدث عن المظهر
and finally, the foundations of respecting
و آخرها احترام الذات
and looking after yourself.
والعناية بها
These six things are crucial starting points
هذه الست نقاط جوهرية
for anyone serious about delivering
لأي شخص جاد في بدء
but tackling this problem is going
و لكن هذه المشكلة
to require each and everyone of us
تتطلب من كل منا
to step up and be better role models
المبادرة بأن تكون قدوة حسنة
for the women and girls in our own lives.
للنساء والفتيات القريبات منها
Challenging the status quo of how
و تحدي واقع الحال
women are seen and talked about in our own circles.
التي تظهر بها النساء في مجتمعاتنا
It is not okay that we judge the contribution
لا يجب أن نحكم على كفاءة القياديات
of our politicians by their haircuts
من خلال تسريحة الشعر
or the size of their breasts,
أو مقاس الصدر
or to infer that the determination or the success
أو أن نتوقع النجاح للاعبة أولمبية
of an Olympian is down to her not being a looker.
لأنها لا تدير الأعناق لجمالها
We need to start judging people by what they do,
علينا أن نرى الناس بأفعالهم
not what they look like.
لا بمظهرهم
We can all start by taking responsibility for the types of pictures
علينا أن نهتم بنوعية الصور التي ننشرها
and comments that we post
والتعليقات التي نكتبها
on our own social networks.
في الشبكات الإجتماعية
We can compliment people based on their effort
علينا أن نثني على الناس للجهود التي بذلوها
and their actions
و الأعمال التي قاموا بها
and not on their appearance.
وليس على أشكالهم
And let me ask you,
دعوني أسألكم
when was the last time that you
متى كانت آخر مرة
kissed a mirror?
قبلتم فيها مرآة؟
Ultimately, we need to work together
وفي النهاية يجب علينا العمل سويا
as communities, as governments
كمجتمعات و حكومات و رجال أعمال
so that our kids grow up valuing their whole selves,
ليتربى أطفالنا على تقدير ذواتهم
valuing individuality, diversity, inclusion.
و احترام التفرد و الإختلاف و الإنتماء
We need to put the people that are making a real difference
يجب أن نبرز الأشخاص الفاعلين
on our pedestals, making a difference
في المجتمع كقدوات
in the real world.
الأشخاص الفارقين في العالم
Giving them the airtime, because only then
و نسلط عليهم الأضواء
will we create a different world.
وعند فعل ذلك، عندها يمكننا صنع التغيير
A world where our kids are free to become
نريد صنع عالم يشعر أطفالنا فيه بالحرية
the best versions of themselves,
بأن يكونوا أفضل ما يمكنهم
where the way they think they look
عالم حيث اعتبارهم لمظهرهم
never holds them back from being who they are
لا يعيقهم عما يطمحون إليه
or achieving what they want in life.
أو عن تحقيق ما يريدون في الحياة
Think about what this might mean for someone in your life.
فكروا مالذي سيعنيه كل هذا لأحد في حياتك
Who have you got in mind?
من الذي خطر ببالك؟
Is it your wife?
هل هي زوجتك؟
Your sister?
أختك؟
Your daughter?
ابنتك؟
Your niece?
ابنه اخاك؟
Your friend? It could just be the woman a couple of seats away
صديقتك؟ أو قد تكون المرأة التي تبعد عنك
from you today.
بمقعدين الآن
What would it mean for her
مالذي سيعنيه لها
if she were freed from that voice
إن تحررت من ذاك الصوت
of her inner critic, nagging her to have
الناقد بداخلها، والذي يقلقها
longer legs, thinner thighs, smaller stomach,
لتجعل سيقانها أطول أو أفخاذها أنحف
shorter feet?
أو بطنها أصغر أو قدمها أنعم؟
What could it mean for her if we overcame this
مالذي سيعنيه لها إن تغلبنا على هذا الأمر
and unlocked her potential in that way?
وانطلقت امكانياتها بسبب ذلك؟
Right now, our culture's obsession
اليوم، هوس ثقافتنا بالصورة
with image is holding us all back.
يعيقنا عن التقدم
But let's show our kids the truth.
ولكن دعونا نري أطفالنا الحقيقة
Let's show them that the way you look
دعنا نريهم أن مظهرهم
is just one part of your identity
هو جزء واحد فقط من هويتهم
and that the truth is we love them
وأننا نحبهم
for who they are
لذواتهم
and what they do
و أفعالهم
and how they make us feel.
وللمشاعر التي يحسسونا بها
Let's build self-esteem into our school curriculums.
دعونا ندمج تقدير الذات في مناهج مدارسنا
Let's each and every one of us change the way
دعونا نغير الطريقة
we talk and compare ourselves to other people.
التي نقارن بها أنفسنا مع الآخرين
And let's work together as communities,
دعونا نعمل معا كمجتمعات
from grassroots to governments,
من الجذور إلى الحكومات
so that the happy little one-year-olds
لنجعل الأطفال السعداء اليوم،
of today become the confident
صناع التغيير
changemakers of tomorrow.
الواثقين بأنفسهم غدا
Let's do this.
دعونا نفعل ذلك
(Applause)
(تصفيق)